In the Pokémon Universe, you can throw
your kids out when they are 12.
But, if you use your bike indoors,
you get the DEATH PENALTY.
(Rest in fucking peace headphone users, oh my God.)
They release two Pokémon games every
time and I picked Ruby, like everyone,
because that is an epic monster
that can eradicate worlds,
and that is... that's an overpriced aquarium fish.
The game starts with a Professor, explaining
what Pokémons are.
A Professor of Pokémon, huh?
Parents must be proud...
You get to pick a gender, I picked a girl...
because the guy's name is Brendan,
who names their kids Brendan??
At least in the first game, the name was Red,
and that's a conversation starter.
Speaking of Red, I guess I should name her Ruby?
But that's a stripper name.
So I went with Spike.
Spike is a cool name, for cool people.
We see Spike in a moving van.
There are lots of epic video game openings,
but you can't beat the moving van.
Also, why is she in the back?! I'm starting to believe this
whole "throwing kids out at 12" is not a common thing.
It's just that her parents hate her.
Welcome to your new hometown, Littleroot, that
you are going to be in for seven minutes.
This is the new house, where three people are
supposed to live, but there is only one bed.
In the Pokémon world, families are a bit... TOO close.
Through a television broadcast, we find out that the reason we moved here was because the dad has become the new Gym Leader two towns away.
You would expect him to move there, but
Hoenn has a serious housing shortage.
This small town of two houses and a lab has
three homeless people.
Our neighbor is the Professor, so we go there,
but he is not there.
There he is!! And if we don't save him,
he is going to have his arm ripped off by a rabid dog.
We get to pick a Pokémon. I am a big fan of
classical art and my favorite kinds are...
memes from 2006.
So, I picked Mudkip.
You kill the cute doggy, then you get to keep the
Mudkip, then you get to face your rival, Brendan,
who has a Pokémon, that yours is weak against,
and this is the actual reason I picked a
girl character, because now I can easily
call Brendan a massive cunt.
After you humiliate him, the Professor tells you
to go meet your dad in the Petalburg Gym.
(as Norman)
"Spike, you need to defeat 8 Gym Leaders, like me,
to gain access to the Pokémon League...
and right now, you're too awful to defeat me."
"I could defeat my dad when I was six."
"You are an embarrassment to our family,
and to our ancestors, and I hate you."
So we're off to beat the first Gym Leader
in Rustboro City.
But first, we've got to go through a forest.
Here we meet a member of Team Magma, an
organized crime syndicate that has realized that
there is just no money in heroin,
and if you want to make some serious cash,
you've gotta increase the planet's landmass.
When you defeat these guys, why do
they give you money?
Is it a bribe?
The first Gym is a Rock Gym, owned by...
I don't allow puns in my videos...
The first Gym is owned by Ace.
A cool name... for cool people.
And she goes down in three hits.
Why is this necessary to get into the Pokémon League?
Showing THIS at the entrance should
LOWER my chances.
The next Gym is on an island.
How will we get there?
You see, the CEO of a million-dollar
corporation wants you to deliver a letter,
and he's not gonna stand in line in the post office,
and telephones are for weak people...
and while we are on this boat, let me tell you
my Pokémon story.
I used to watch the second series.
There were two series'.
One was horrible. It was about this kid named Ash,
who said "I'm gonna do something!",
Then he did fuck all for 7,000 episodes.
But the other one was the greatest thing.
It was about these kids, they had Pokémon,
then they penetrated a giant vampire.
( ͡° ͜ʖ ͡°)
I did also play the games.
I remember being very sad when I realized
that Pokémons weren't real.
Then my uncle told me not to be so sure,
and that's when he took me to my very first dogfight.
It was mesmerizing. Like the games came to life.
That was sixteen years ago.
If you want to feel really old,
the release of Ruby is closer to the moon
landing than today.
On the island, we find the second Gym,
a Fighting-type Gym,
the least creative Pokémon type.
I mean, there are Water Pokémons, there are
Fire Pokémons, there are Psychic Pokémons...
then there are Pokémons who f-fight...
I kick his arse.
Turns out your fists can't protect you
against throwing mud.
When defeating this guy, you can now
use the HM move, Flash.
HM moves are moves you can use
outside of battle.
They are mostly useless, can't be removed, and are
most likely a torture experiment, created by Nintendo.
You deliver this letter to this blue-haired freak.
But the CEO also wanted you to deliver some
parcel to a man named Captain Stern,
in Slateport City.
Cannot really blame him for that one, though.
I'd trust a random twelve-year old over UPS.
We get to Slateport, we go to the Museum,
give the package to Stern...
then we are robbed.
There is, apparently, no law enforcement in
this entire country.
So, maybe invest in some security, Captain.
After you defeat those two, the
leader of Magma shows up.
(as Maxie)
"Stop being in our way. Increasing the planet's
landmass is just a harmless hobby."
"Also, this guy in my Golf club won't shut
up about his beach house."
"Won't be... so braggy... soon... Robert..."
Then they leave, and I fished on every corner,
and caught the aquarium fish.
The next Gym is in Mauville City.
It's an Electricity Gym...
and Water is weak against Electricity...
but, apparently, Lightning can't protect you
against getting mud in your face.
Then, for some reason, the story completely stops,
and the game tells you to spend a couple of hours walking across the ENTIRE NATION.
Finally, you get to a cave, where Team Magma
has stolen a Meteorite from Professor Cosmos.
Okay, first of all, BUY A GUN.
Second, "Professor Cosmos"??
Did you seriously change your name
when you got your Ph.D?!
Then, you have to travel to the top of a volcano,
where you, once again, meet the
leader of Team Magma.
(as Maxie)
"I'm going to use this energy-filled meteorite
to make this volcano go 'BOOM!'"
"So that in a hundred years, there will be a bit
more fully habitable land."
"Obviously hundreds of people and Pokémon will die."
"But you can stop all this by defeating my three
Pokémon right now, no pressure."
"Aw, darnit! No mass murdering today!"
Then, he leaves, and did... not take his
meteorite with him...
You reach a city that can only be
reached by going down from the volcano,
so their economy should be in shambles...
but it doesn't look like it...
but then you find out they have a...
and it all makes sense.
There's a Gym here too.
It's a Fire Gym,
and what I did in there goes against
the Geneva Convention.
Time for us to face Dad. The theme of
Dad's Gym is... item use,
and that has got to be the worst
theme I have ever heard.
How did that come about?
(as Pokémon HR Guy)
"Uh, congratulations on becoming a Gym Leader,
now what will be your Gym's theme?"
(as Norman)
"I'll need you to call up the other Gym Leaders,
and tell them that they can't use items anymore,
and if they disagree, I'm gonna sue 'em!"
Defeating your dad gives you the ability
to traverse water.
Ruby has... a lot of water.
I wouldn't lower a review score because of it...
because that's STUPID.
But, damn it, that's the seventeenth time!
Kinda makes you sympathize with Team Magma.
Speaking of Team Magma, you find them
once again, northwest of the Electricity Gym.
They are robbing a weather station.
I don't understand why.
They are weather scientists, not NATO.
The next Gym is in Fortree City,
a treehouse city.
"Why you don't outsource city planning to a preschool."
It has a bird Gym.
Sadly, the Game Boy Advance is not powerful
enough to render all of the bird shit.
After that's done, you get informed to travel to Mt. Pyre,
and on top of that mountain, you meet
the Magma Team Leader again.
(as Maxie)
"Ha, you're too late! To wake up an ancient,
maybe-not-real Pokémon, I have stolen this
precious Blue Orb from these elderly folks."
"Ugh... what am I doing with my life?"
Then, the old people give Spike the
opposite "Red Orb".
Could you imagine if the Mona Lisa was stolen again,
and the Louvre was like,
"Well that sucks, who wants Aphrodite?!"
(The accent really makes it sounds like "Aprodatie")
You have to go back to Captain Stern,
and then you see Team Magma steal
a submarine, and then...
Wait! Did they just...
... I have so many questions...
It is decided that Spike should attack Team
Magma's base head-on.
Sounds like a suicide mission, but it turns out
not only the good guys have forgotten to
invest in some security.
I am literally robbing these people right now.
Am... am I the bad guy?
"Master Ball"?
Well, I guess I'm using it!
But, we are too late, they have already left,
and they are going to use the Blue Orb,
to awaken that Red Monster,
so that it can evaporate the world's water,
and billions of people will die.
But I can't go after them, because I need
to beat this Gym first,
so that my Pokémon are
allowed to go underwater.
Not that I need to save the world or anything, you twats.
We find the sub, we go in, and
(as Maxie)
"Oh no, the Red Monster is awake
and we can't control him!"
Waking him makes the sun more bright in...
THIS area.
Not a hole in the Ozone Layer, just,
the sun is brighter. How does that even work?
Does the Sun look down on Earth, and
when he sees that Red fella he's like,
(as The Sun)
"OY! FOKK THAT GUY!"
This is actually somewhat epic for
Game Boy Advance, and
(Battle Music starts)
OH, COME ON!!
Not that it matters, you can trade a level 4 sloth with this raccoon,
and then get the cover model.
There's one more Gym and, spoiler alert, I win.
Then you go through a cave that feels like
the longest in video games,
and finally, we are here, in front of the
Pokémon League and I am too weak.
Time for a Training Montage!
(warped Digimon theme music intensifies)
There we go~!
Now, I have defeated the Elite Four...
I might have overtrained for this...
But now I am about to face the champion...
and it's the blue-haired guy we delivered
the letter to! What a twist!!
I didn't overtrain for this!
Everyone else undertrained!
I liked Ruby, but it needs way more water,
Worst game ever,
And that is the Kilian Experience.
Subscribe for more garbage.
So, I just hit 10,000 subscribers, but
my only dream since starting this channel is
to do a Q&A video with unrelated
Call of Duty footage in the background.
Leave questions in the comments!!